Don't miss the climax.
Fifty Shades Freed is a drama, romance film directed by James Foley.
Believing they have left behind shadowy figures from their past, newlyweds Christian and
Ana fully embrace an inextricable connection and shared life of luxury.
But just as she steps into her role as Mrs.
Grey and he relaxes into an unfamiliar stability, new threats could
jeopardize their happy ending before it even begins.
Anastasia Steele, played by Dakota Johnson.
Christian Grey, played by Jamie Dornan.
Jack Hyde, played by Eric Johnson.
Kate Kavanagh, played by Eloise Mumford.
Mia Grey, played by Rita Ora.
Elliot Grey, played by Luke Grimes.
Fifty Shades Freed is a 2018 American erotic romantic drama film directed
by James Foley and written by Niall Leonard, based on E.
James's 2012 novel of the same name.
Produced by Perfect World Pictures, Michael De Luca Productions, and Trigger Street Productions, and distributed by Universal Pictures, it is the
third and final installment in the Fifty Shades film series, following Fifty Shades of Grey (2015) and Fifty Shades Darker (2017).
The film stars Dakota Johnson and Jamie Dornan as Anastasia Steele and Christian Grey, respectively, and follows the
couple as they marry, and must deal with Ana's former boss Jack Hyde (Eric Johnson), who begins to stalk them.
The film marked Foley's final directorial effort before his death in 2025.
Following the first film's premiere in February 2015,
development on the sequels promptly began.
By November 2015, Foley and Leonard were respectively hired to direct and
write both sequels, which would be shot back-to-back in 2016.
Principal photography on Fifty Shades Freed began simultaneously with Darker in
February 2016, in Paris and Vancouver, and ended in July 2016.
Composer Danny Elfman, who had scored the previous films,
returned to compose the score for the final film.
Fifty Shades Freed premiered in Paris on February 6, 2018, and was released in the United
States by Universal Pictures on February 9, including a limited IMAX release.
Despite being a box office success, grossing $372 million worldwide against a production
budget of $55 million, it was the lowest-grossing film of the trilogy.
Like its two predecessors, Fifty Shades Freed received unfavorable
reviews, with criticism for its screenplay and acting.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book, eroticism, sequel, bdsm.
The tone is emotional.